Nakul Deshmukh

217, Vinkar Colony, Nagpur 🏦

+91-9028838663

Nakuldeshmukh619@gmail.com <a>

@nakuldex in

Passionate Automation developer with 5+ years of experience. Built the skill set by diversifying portfolio includes role as Jr. Developer, Associate, SPOC, Sr. Developer, SME, Lead etc. Results oriented in the automation opportunity searching and implementation. Highly motivated in automating stuffs with creative, quality, and smart approaches. Looking forward for interesting challenges to undertake!

Skills

- Python, Core Java
- Selenium, Pandas
- GIT, Jira

- Automation Anywhere, UiPath
- Linux, Docker, Jenkins
- APIs using Flask, Redis

30/3/2017 - TILL DATE

Company / Wipro Technologies

Project Experience

1/4/2021 - TILL DATE

Sr. Automation Developer, SME / Intel Account, Bangalore

- Contributed to Automation as a service project.
- Core member in product automation testing framework development from scratch. Automated 400+ UI, CLI and API based TCs. Contributed in the CICD pipeline creation.
- Delivering solutions as an Automation SME for various accounts of the Wipro. Got recognition for the automation work across the organization.
- Developed high standards, end-to-end, easy to maintain credit management 4+ automations that have saved 1100+ hours of manual efforts.
- Fixed and optimized production critical 10+ scripts on time for the Diversey account.
- Developed API bases automation for McGrow Hill Account.
- Built resume parser automation for HR group.
- **Skills**: Python, Selenium, Pandas, Flask, Linux, Docker, Jenkins, UiPath.

1/4/2018 - 31/3/2021

Automation SPOC / Chemours Account, Pune

- Instrumental in initial setup and stabilizing this new project. Involved in defining and executing new processes/operations/teams.
- Delivered high quality improvements and automations in operations, lean, databases, APIs, monitoring, and reporting that proved effective in managing SLA. Enabled 99% SLA adherence.
 Worked closely with clients across the globe, understood the problem statements and independently delivered creative, end-to-end solutions/automations.
- Independently delivered 80+ automation use cases that has extensively saved manual efforts.

- Worked as a member of four teams and lead the automation team. Received recognitions/awards for multiple instances. Made the scripts with high code quality and easily maintainable for better life cycle.
- **Skills**: Automation Anywhere, Sikuli, Power automate, PowerShell, Concur, Team management, Communication, and reporting.

1/6/2017 - 31/3/2018

Jr. Software Developer / Nokia Account, Chennai

- Started career with Wipro Technologies.
- Contributed to the Nokia NPT version upgrade development and stability improvement work. Worked on the backend with Core Java skill. Quickly adapted the Java and started delivering.
- Skills: Java, Git, Jira.

Education

MARCH 2022

Master of Technology (IT) / VIT, Chennai

Received M. Tech (IT) integrated degree from VIT, Chennai with 8.3 CGPA.

AUGUST 2016

Bachelor of Statistics / Institute Of Science, Nagpur

Received B. Stats degree from I. Sc. Nagpur with CGPA 7.0. Awarded with 2nd prize for Inter college presentation competition.

Recognitions:

- Star of the Month: Chemours, Pune 2018, for accurately building and tracking project SLA reports.
- Best performer: Chemours, Pune 2019, for DOA process building and lean.
- Star performer: Intel, Bangalore 2021, for Automation work.
- Consistent performer: various projects 2021-2022, For contribution in different accounts/projects across organization.